《使女的故事》前情提要
Previously on The Handmaid's Tale...
你将成为全球大使 作为我们神圣共和国的代表
You'll be acting as a global ambassador to represent our sacred republic.
你的那个崭新宏图叫什么来着
This new grand plan of yours. What are you calling it?
新伯利恒计划
New Bethlehem.
一个现代化的小岛 基列国难民如果回心转意
A modernized island where Gilead refugees can come home
我们便承诺他们可以在此与失散的亲友团聚
and the promise of reuniting with long-lost family and friends.
布莱恩
Blaine!
- 你差点就杀了她 - 大主教 不是我做的
- You could've fucking killed her! - Commander, it wasn't me!
你丈夫怎么了
What's going on with your husband?
他被逮捕了
He's been arrested.
撞我的那个人死了
The man who ran me over died.
她生气也是应该的
She's right to be upset with me.
萝丝一直很敏感
Rosie's always been sensitive.
你不打算回华盛顿吗
You're, uh, not going back to D.C.?
我不在一时半刻也出不了问题
I think they can get by without me... for a while.
我们不能就这么认输
We can't just let them win.
五月天还在反抗
Mayday's fighting back.
你肯定需要人越过边境 打入内部
You must need people to cross the border, get inside.
我想帮忙
I wanna help.
我这有些文件需要你签字 关于我们协议的细则
I have some papers for you to sign. They outline our agreement.
我很期待和你共事
I look forward to working together.
如果我在加拿大被捕 他们就会把诺亚交给惠勒夫妇
If I'm arrested in Canada, they will give Noah back to the Wheelers,
我就再也见不到他了
and I will never see him again.
琼 救救我
June! June!
赛丽娜 你必须下车
Serena, you have to get off the train.
我做不到
I can't do it.
琼
June!
琼·奥斯本
June Osborn!
使女的故事 第六季第二集
好了 好了
Oh, okay. Okay.
上帝永远与我们同在
God is with us always.
锡安山教堂 始建于1856年 重建于1893年
你好
Hello?
你好 需要帮助吗
Hi there. Do you need some help?
你好 我是阿比盖尔 欢迎来到迦南
Hi there. I'm Abigail. Welcome to Canaan.
迦南 圣经中的地名
愿主的恩典 怜悯和平安与你同在
Grace, mercy and peace.
不过别担心 你还在加拿大
But don't worry, you're still in Canada.
你不是我们这的第一个难民
You're not our first refugee to come through.
我不是难民
Oh, um... I'm not a refugee.
你想待多久都可以
You can stay as long as you like.
我们是一个信仰社区
We're a faith-based community.
这里只有女人和孩子
There's only women and children here.
瞧瞧这个小宝贝
Oh, look at this darling.
孩子是主的恩赐 对吧
Children are a heritage from the Lord, aren't they?
我们该如何称呼你
And what shall we call you?
瑞秋
Uh, Rachel.
好
Okay.
I'll Be Your Mirror - The Velvet Underground & Nico
♪你是如此美丽♪
The beauty you are
♪若你视而不见 让我做你的双眼♪
But if you don't let me be your eyes
♪为你拨开黑雾 驱散担忧♪
A hand to your darkness So you won't be afraid
♪当你自觉黑夜窥探♪
When you think The night has seen your mind
♪你灵魂的乖张孤僻♪
That inside you're twisted and unkind
♪我会证明你被蒙蔽双目♪
Let me stand to show That you are blind
♪请放下双手 因为你在我的眼中♪
Please put down your hands 'Cause I see you
♪我做你的镜子 映照你的真我♪
I'll be your mirror Reflect what you are
♪若你问我在何处 我会化作风♪
In case you don't know I'll be the wind
♪雨水和落日♪
The rain and the sunset
♪门前盈盈灯光 你在家中 平安无恙♪
The light on your door to know that you're home
♪当你...♪
When you think...
她很可爱
Oh, she is adorable.
而且很聪明 太机灵了
And she's so smart. So smart.
当一个小天才可不容易
It's so hard being a little genius.
好啦好啦
There we go.
你好呀 宝贝
Hi, sweetheart.
一个小机灵鬼
A little genius.
你弄到了婴儿围栏
You got a playpen.
是在捐赠车那里找到的
Mm-hmm. From the donation trailer.
这里的人们互相帮扶
Everybody here helps each other.
我想检查一下你的胳膊
I want to take a look at your arm.
不用了 我很好 已经好多了
No, I'm fine. It's a lot better.
- 还疼吗 - 不疼了
- Is it still throbbing? - No, no.
好多了 药效起作用了
It's much better. The meds helped,
睡一觉也很有帮助
and sleep helped.
你知道的 我可以帮你摘掉它
You know, I can remove that for you.
我做过许多次了
I've done it before. Many times.
你可以摆脱它
You can leave that behind.
不用了
No.
我不能 除非所有的使女都获得自由
No, I can't. Not until all the Handmaids are free.
那好吧 我给你做些吃的 煎饼怎么样
Well then, let me fix something for you. How about pancakes?
好 听起来很不错
Okay. Sounds pretty good.
好的
Okay.
我们找过你
We... We looked for you.
我们去了你的公寓
We went to your apartment.
大门敞开着 他们撕毁了你所有的书籍
The door was open and they'd torn apart all your books.
他们打碎了那座巴西的雕塑 毁掉了整个公寓
They'd smashed that statue from Brazil. They... They destroyed everything.
是啊
Hmm. Yeah.
他们把我拖出去
They dragged me out.
然后在私设法庭上审判我
And they tried me in their kangaroo court.
戴着面具 我都看不到他们的脸
Wearing masks. I couldn't even see their faces.
一群胆小鬼
Pussies.
我看到了你在殖民地的照片
I saw a picture of you in the Colonies.
我以为
I thought...
你怎么活下来的
How did you survive that?
一个医生还是能派上点用场
Well, a doctor's useful.
他们叫我去照顾嬷嬷和守卫
They made me take care of the Aunts and the Guardians.
他们囚禁了我们 杀害了我的朋友们
They kept us prisoner and killed my friends.
但我挺过来了
But I hung on.
能再见到你的念头支撑我咬牙走下去
With the hope that I might see you some day.
这念头又是从何而起
What made you do that?
我了解你 也清楚是如何抚养你长大的
I know you. And I know how I raised you.
不管处境多么糟糕 我都坚信你一定还活着
And no matter how bad it got, I always had faith that you'd survive.
而现在 你就在我面前
And now, here you are.
妈 你是怎么逃出来的
How did you escape, Mom?
是军队救了我
It was the Army.
大概六个月前 他们解放了我所在的殖民地
They liberated my Colony about six months ago.
- 美国军队吗 - 对
- The US Army? - Yeah.
残余部队
What's left of 'em.
我被送到这里后一直在找你
I got sent here and I tried to find out about you.
但基列国封锁了阿拉斯加
But, you know, Gilead's cut Alaska off.
没有网络 没有手机 没有新闻
No Internet, no cell, no news. So...
我们每周能用五分钟公共电话
We have five minutes a week at the public phones.
如其他数百万人一样 我联系了能找到的
So I called every embassy, every refugee agency I could find,
每一个大使馆和难民署
along with millions of other people.
但这些求助都石沉大海 所以...
But I could never get through to anyone that could help me, so I just...
我只能下一周继续尝试
I came back the next week and tried again.
一次又一次 我能做的只有这些
And again and again. That's all I could do.
这个营地本应该是临时居所
This camp was, of course, meant to be temporary, but...
是去往下一程的临时歇脚点
You know, just a way station before moving on.
去哪里
To where?
阿拉斯加的某处
Somewhere else in Alaska.
夏威夷的某地
Or a spot in Hawaii.
关岛 候补名单长着呢
Or Guam. The waitlists are long.
夏威夷是个好地方
Hawaii would have been nice.
不 我想尽可能长久地待在这里
No, I wanted to stay here as long as I could.
为什么
Why?
为了你 亲爱的
For you, sweetheart.
我在等你
I was waiting for you and...
汉娜怎么样了
So, what happened with Hannah?
他们抓捕我的时候也带走了她
Well, they took her when they captured me.
他们把她交给了某对大主教夫妇
And they gave her to a Commander and a wife.
但她...她还活着
But, you know, she's... she's alive.
我...我见到她了
I've... I've seen her.
我见过她了 她很好
Yeah, I've seen her. She's good.
她...她很健康
She's... She's healthy,
十分美丽
and she's so beautiful.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我真的试过救她
And I have really tried to save her.
我真的拼尽全力了
I've really tried to get her out.
我几乎就成功了
I've gotten so close, so close.
但是...
But, you know...
但我最后一次见到她时 妈妈 她...
But, um, the last time I saw her, Mom, she, um...
她不记得我了 所以...
She didn't remember me, so...
亲爱的
Oh, sweetheart.
但没关系 她依旧美丽动人
But it's okay. She is still so beautiful.
你很坚强
Oh, you are tough.
但这还没有结束
But it is not over.
圣克莱尔-维克斯福特拘留所
嘿 老兄
Hey, man.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
他们到阿拉斯加了吗
Did they make it to Alaska?
- 安全抵达 - 真的吗
- Yeah. - Yeah?
马克收到了火车到站的消息
Yeah, Mark got word their train arrived.
太好了 我们能给他们打电话吗
All right. Can we call 'em?
不行 那里没有手机信号
No, we can't. There's no cell service.
也不可能搞到手机 我相信她也在努力
And it's impossible to get to a phone. I'm sure she's been trying.
谢谢你救我出来
Hey. Thanks for getting me out, man.
感谢你做的一切
Like, thanks for everything.
我只是把你从拘留所捞出来
I got you out of jail.
依然在努力推进你的听证会
I'm still working on expediting your hearing.
那得花多久
How long's that gonna take?
大概三四个月
Three, maybe four months.
- 四个月 -四个月
- Four months - Four months?
他从一个变态手中救了他老婆
He saved his wife from a fucking psychopath.
而卢克是对加拿大公民实施犯罪的难民
And Luke's a refugee who committed a crime against a Canadian citizen.
也就是说我被困在这儿了
So I'm just stuck here.
我受不了这堆破事
I can't take this shit.
他们光天化日之下撞倒了琼
They ran June down in the street, man!
他们击落了你们的飞机 我救不了汉娜
They shot down your planes. I can't save Hannah.
那不是你的错
That wasn't your fault.
我不在乎
I don't care!
我女儿还在他们手里
They still got my daughter.
你知道他们会对小女孩做什么 对吧
You know... You know what they do to those girls, right? Right?
你知道他们会对小女孩做什么吗
Do you know what they do to those girls?
- 是吧 - 我知道
- Yes? Yes. - I do.
她每一天都在长大
And she's getting older every fucking day.
我不能坐以待毙 我得采取行动 我得...
I'm not gonna sit here and wait. All right? I gotta do something. So...
我该做什么
So what?
你说啊
- 五月天在采取行动 - 什么
- Mayday is doing something. - What?
等下 他们在做什么
Wait. What? What...What are they doing?
他们要查明是哪些大主教下令击落飞机
They want to identify the Commanders who shot our planes down
阻止你们和汉娜见面
and kept you from Hannah.
然后把他们都杀了
And kill them.
我加入
I'm in.
你根本不知道这代表什么
Wait, you don't even know what that means.
不重要 我加入
It doesn't matter. I'm in.
我要加入
I'm in.
那里没刷到
You missed that spot.
你拿着那个做什么 还给我
What are you doing with that? Give me those.
等等 你别动 是我让她拿的
Wait. No. Stop, I asked her to take those.
为什么
Why?
因为我想把它们放到地下室
Because I'd like to put them in the basement.
我们不是说好了吗
We talked about this.
这个房子别的都听你的
You can do whatever you want in the rest of the house,
但书房我说了算
but the study is mine.
是 但我们也说好要把房子布置得典雅宜居
Yes, but we also talked about making the house look civilized.
这很典雅宜居啊
And the house does look civilized.
但那堆东西很难看 它们毁了整个房间
But those are ugly, and they ruin the room.
这个房间存在的意义就是安置我的物品
The reason I have this room is so that I can keep my things in it.
祈神保佑 大主教
Blessed day, Commander.
- 嘿 小子 - 祈神保佑
- Hi, champ. - Blessed day.
请进
Come on in.
别动这些 拜托
Don't touch these, please.
我也好歹是个大主教
I'm a Commander.
你是来给我最后一击的吗 我要不要去拿护齿套
You come here to finish the job? Should I grab my mouthguard?
我是来给你提个醒
Actually, I'm just here to give you a heads-up.
我岳父正在来的路上
My father-in-law is on his way over.
听着
Look,
琼的事和我没关系
I had nothing to do with what happened to June.
想弄死她的心情我并不陌生
I'm very familiar with the feeling of wanting to run her over with a truck,
但这次不是我干的
but this time it was not me.
好吧
Okay.
你相信我吗
So, you believe me?
我们这事儿就算过去了
We can move on?
我相信你没有这个实力或者能力
I believe you don't have the power or the capability.
他来了
There he is!
约瑟夫
Joseph.
很高兴见到你
It's always a pleasure.
需要我当裁判吗
You guys need a referee?
不了 我们很好 尼克学会了情绪管理
No, we're good. Nick's learned how to control his anger.
我也掌握了躲避的技巧
And I learned how to duck.
我盯着他呢
I'm still keeping an eye on him.
你还是盯着新伯利恒吧
No, keep your eye on New Bethlehem.
我们快被申请表淹没了
We're drowning in applications.
这地方比布鲁克林任何一所幼儿园都难进
It's harder to get into than any preschool in Brooklyn ever was.
真替你高兴 约瑟夫
I'm happy for you, Joseph. I am.
它很离经叛道 但它建立在仁慈和宽恕之上
It was a crazy idea, but one built on mercy and forgiveness.
为此 我深表钦佩
And for that, I commend you.
谢谢你 加布里埃尔
Hmm. Thank you, Gabriel.
谁能想到经济学家也有心呢
Who knew the numbers guy had a heart?
那你就误会我了 我们会赚大钱的
Well, don't get me wrong. We're gonna make a lot of money.
通过新伯利恒的新贸易路线
The new, uh, trade route through New Bethlehem...
回报颇丰
Is paying off handsomely.
我们出售干净的水源和农产品
We sell clean water and produce,
进口汽车和电子产品 大家都会满意
import cars and electronics... Everyone's happy.
你是如何解决强硬派对安全问题的担忧
And how did you deal with the hardliners on their security concerns?
当他们意识到自己可以穿越边境
Their concerns evaporated the moment they realized
购买豪车名表 担忧就烟消云散了
they could cross the border and pick up a Mercedes and a Rolex.
- 我问个问题 - 请讲
- I have a question for you. - Shoot.
沃特弗德夫人在其中扮演什么角色
Where does Mrs.Waterford fit into this?
- 赛丽娜吗 - 对
- Serena? - Yes.
难道你不希望由她来欢迎基列国公民回家吗
Wouldn't you want her welcoming our citizens back home?
这想法不错
That's not a terrible idea, actually.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
你毕竟让她做了基列国的全球大使
I mean, Joseph, you made her our global ambassador,
但有些时日没听到她的消息了 这是为什么
but we haven't heard anything from her for a while. Why?
她还在惠勒家吗
Is she still at the, um... the Wheelers?
惠勒夫妇现在看来是个大问题
The Wheelers turned out to be problematic.
她又刚生了孩子
And she just had a child.
需要时间恢复 休产假之类的
She needs time to recuperate. Maternity leave and all that.
你懂的 产妇相关那些事
You know, lady business.
我又懂什么呢
Hmm. Well, what do I know?
但你至少希望她能在此参与外交访问吧
But I would think you would want her here for the diplomatic visits at the least.
- 不 - 啊
- No! - Whoa!
天 什么情况
Oh, come on! What the hell?
安吉拉 你怎么在桌子下面
Angela, what are you doing down...
内奥米 来把孩子带出去
Naomi! Come and get your child!
我们在开会呢
We're trying to have a meeting.
她只是个孩子
She's just a little kid.
来 叔叔抱
Hey, come here. Oh!
我们去找妈妈 离这个老古板远一点好不好
What do you say, we go see your mother and get rid of this Grumpy Gus here, hmm?
妈妈在哪儿呢
Where is she?
我们得把赛丽娜找回来
We need to get Serena back.
如果沃顿让你跳桥...
If Wharton asked you to jump off a bridge...
我会爬上最高那座桥 祈求上帝垂青
No, I'd find the highest one and hope for the best.
我们就不能...
Uh... Can't we just like...
非得让她掺合这些事吗
Do we have to drag her back into all this?
你知道她在哪儿吗
Do you know where she is?
不 不知道 我只是...
No. No, I just...
我去问问眼目 看他们是否有线索
I can talk to the Eyes. See if they have any leads.
好 找到她
Good. Find her.
是时候让赛丽娜回到基列国了
Time to bring Serena back to Gilead.
我不能待在这儿
Nah, I'm not... I'm not staying here.
我理解你想帮忙
Okay, yeah, I get why you want to help.
但没人知道你会遭遇什么
But who knows what you're getting into.
我们会小心行事
We'll be careful.
你家那边怎么了
Hey, what's going on with your place?
楼下那户人家今早被赶走 送去收容所了
Uh, well, the family downstairs got booted this morning and sent to a shelter.
他们只能把大半家当留在街上
They had to leave half their stuff on the street.
- 狗屎政府 - 是啊
- The fucking government. - Mm-hmm.
我知道下一个就是我
And I know I'm next.
我会帮你
I'll help you.
我们都会被赶出去 迟早的事 莫伊拉
They're pushing all of us out, so it's just a matter of time, Moira.
我可能会去一趟新伯利恒
I, um, I... I might visit New Bethlehem.
别去 丽塔
Rita, no.
他们或许有我妹妹的消息
They might have a lead on my sister.
我理解 但他们不值得信任
Look, I get that, but you can't trust them.
好吧
Okay.
- 是琼 - 我来
- Oh, this is her. - All right.
别跟她提我们要做的事 好吗
Don't say anything about what we're doing. All right?
喂 琼
Hey, June?
- 卢克吗 - 嗨
- Luke? - Hey.
等会儿 怎么会是你
What? Luke, what are you doing?
- 是卢克 你出来了 - 是的
- It's Luke! Luke, are you out? - Yeah, yeah.
- 马克帮忙找了关系 - 你开免提
- Mark pulled some strings. - Put her on the voice...
我把免提打开
I'm gonna... I'll put you on speaker. I'm putting you on speaker.
- 嗨 - 琼
- Hi! - June!
你们好
Hi! Hi!
你和妮可都还好吗
How are you? How's Nichole?
她很好 妮可很好
Oh, she's, um... She's good. Nichole's good.
我们这儿...稍等 等一下
We're... We're here. But here, hold on one second, okay?
我想你们和她打个招呼
I want you to say hi to someone.
你好 卢克
Hello, Luke.
- 霍莉 是你吗 - 是霍莉吗 我的天
- Holly? - Holly? Oh, my God!
- 是莫伊拉吗 - 难以置信
- Moira? - Are you serious?
- 霍莉 - 你还好吗
- Holly! - Are you all right?
很好 别担心 她们也被我照顾得很好
Yes. Yes. And don't you worry. I'm taking good care of these girls.
我们打电话的时间有限
And listen, we don't get much time on these calls.
我们回头再聊
So I'll see you soon.
- 好吧 爱你 - 再见
- Okay, I love you! - Bye.
好 我等下就来
Okay. Be right there.
- 琼 - 是我
- Hey, June? - Hi.
居然是你妈妈 这真的太棒了
Your mom? That's fucking...That's amazing. That's so good.
是的 我知道
I know. I know. I know.
你和妮可 你们是坐火车到那儿的吗
And you and Nichole... You got there on the train all right?
是的 我们还好
Yeah. Yeah, we're okay.
我们没事的
We're okay.
琼
June?
怎么了
你不会相信
You won't believe...
但赛丽娜也在火车上
You won't believe this, but Serena was on the train with...
她带着诺亚
with Noah.
等等 赛丽娜也在
Wait, Serena?
怎么会呢
How was that?
我不知道 我不知道他们怎么样了
Luke, I don't know. I don't know what happened to them.
所以...
So...
还有很多人在排队打电话
Anyway, I don't have much time.
现在什么情况
So can you tell me what's happening?
他们会撤销你的案件 还是...
Are they gonna dismiss your case, or...
不 我得等听证会结束
No, I've gotta wait for my hearing.
好吧 要等多久
Okay, how long is that?
- 好几个月吧 - 什么
- It's a couple of months... - What?
我知道
I know, I know.
- 马克有最棒的律师团队... - 靠
- Mark's got the best lawyers... - Shit!
我们这个案子论据充分
And we've got a really strong case. Yeah.
- 别担心 - 好吧
- So don't worry about me. - Okay, all right. Okay.
那我们只能等待了
Well, we'll just... wait.
我们等
We'll wait.
我们每周只能打一次电话 但我会打给你的
We only get one call a week, but I will call you.
下周我会打给你 好吗
I will call you next week. Okay?
好 你一定要打
Okay. All right. All right. You better.
我会的
I will. I will.
我很想你
I miss you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
琼和妮可还好吗
June and Nichole safe?
她们坐火车到了阿拉斯加
Their train made it to Alaska.
已经加密过了
It's encrypted.
要是我打来的时候你没法接 之后尽快给我回电
If you can't pick up when I call, try me back ASAP.
以及 我们需要基列巡逻队
Also... we need the schedule of Gilead patrols
在标记区域的巡逻时间表
in the marked areas.
在无人区的吗
In No Man's Land?
为什么美国军方要了解我们的巡逻区域
Why does the US military need to know our patrol zones?
还是说五月天在谋划什么
Or is Mayday trying something?
五月天是什么
What's Mayday?
要知道 你们接受过准军事训练
You know, you ran through the paramilitary.
五月天那些人可没有
Those people you get from Mayday, they're not trained.
他们是老师 药师 优步司机
They're teachers and pharmacists, Uber drivers.
他们相信自由 想要复国
They believe in freedom. They want their country back.
那他们是毫无机会了
Well, they don't stand a chance.
卫士会抓住他们 把他们直接交给眼目
The Guardians will capture them and give them straight to the Eyes
或者当场枪毙
or just shoot them on the spot.
你还要让多少人飞蛾扑火
How many bodies are you gonna let them throw in the fire?
到底什么时候才是个头
When is enough, enough?
直到无人可战
When there's no one left to fight.
两个月后
这是妈妈最喜欢的绘本之一
Ooh! This is one of Mommy's favorites.
多好呀
Ah, yes!
不过真是可怜人啊 她凡事都得亲力亲为
Poor thing, though. She had to do everything by herself.
没人帮她
No one to help her.
你敢相信吗
Yeah. Can you believe that?
Can you believe that?
我想我会信
Think I might.
它们长势喜人啊
Those are coming in nicely.
你今天摘了多少土豆呢 小家伙
And how many tomatoes did you pick today, little man?
他睡了一整天 一点忙没帮上
Oh, he was no help at all. He slept the whole day.
别踩到我的杜鹃
Don't step on my azaleas.
就只有一次 爸爸
Ah. It was one time, Dad.
就那一次
One time.
真高兴你回来了 我的小羊羔
Glad to have you home, lamb.
回来感觉真好
It's good to be back.
新书宣传怎么样
How's the book tour?
规模很小 但读者反应热烈
Small. But people seem to really be responding.
他们渴望改变
They're hungry for change.
渴望信仰
Faith.
我从布道坛上看到了信仰
I see it from my pulpit.
这是黑暗时日
These are dark days.
人们需要相信些什么
People need to believe in something.
我很高兴他们仰仗的是你
I'm glad they're looking to you.
咱们去弄点柠檬水吧
Now, let's go get some lemonade.
我想听听那个缠着你不放的男孩
I want to hear all about that boy who won't leave you alone.
他叫弗莱德
His name is Fred.
弗莱德
Fred.
劳伦斯把他的未来全都押在新伯利恒上了
Lawrence has completely tied his future to New Bethlehem.
还有你的未来
And yours.
我想他会说是基列国的未来
I think he'd say Gilead's future.
你知道为什么我们自称"雅各的子孙"吗
Do you know why we call ourselves "Sons of Jacob"?
雅各 又称以色列 是以撒的幼子 犹太人的祖先
因为太多人没有真正的父亲 只能独自摸索前进
It's because too many of us had to make do without real fathers.
我知道令堂已经尽己所能
And I know your mother tried her best,
但她要离家工作 对吧
but she had to work outside the home, didn't she?
她喜欢她的工作
Well, she liked her job.
她当然喜欢
I'm sure she did.
没有哪个母亲会在餐馆后厨
No mother would choose to cook at a diner
和自家厨房之间选择前者
instead of for her own family at home.
我知道令尊是个很难相处的人
I know your father was a difficult man.
相当体面的说法
That's, uh... That's one way of putting it.
曾经是沃特弗德
Waterford.
如今是劳伦斯
Now, Lawrence.
你让这些男性尊长走入你的人生 成为你的向导
You've let these men come into your life and guide you.
我从未混淆过
Look, I've never been confused
他们在我人生中扮演的角色
about the roles they played in my life.
嗯...
Well...
你也快做父亲了
You'll be a father soon.
你会为自己的儿子树立榜样
And you'll set the standard for your son.
记住
And remember,
每一次做选择的时候
every choice you make,
问问自己在给儿子树立何种榜样
ask yourself what kind of example you're setting for him.
他会做何感想
How's he gonna feel?
这对他有益还是有害
Will this help him or hurt him?
好好抉择 孩子
Make good choices, son.
这就是你需要做的
That's all you have to do.
你潜力无穷
You have so much potential.
您拨打的电话暂时无法接通
The person you are trying to reach is not available.
请在提示音后留言
Please leave a message after the tone.
嘿 亲爱的 是我 嗯
Hey, honey, it's me. Um...
我给你打过好几次电话了
I've tried you a few times.
我开始担心了
I'm starting to get worried.
所以
So...
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我只是想知道你的听证会是不是已经开过了
Uh, just wondering if you had your hearing.
我想可能是 但...
Thought maybe it'd happened but, um...
请快点 女士
Come on, lady.
好的
Okay.
你能不能
Look, can you please just...
下次尽量接个电话 好吗
Just try to pick up next time, all right?
因为打电话很难 我会一直打的 但...
Because it's really hard to call and I'm gonna keep trying, but...
好吧
Okay.
老天啊 我只希望平安
God, I just hope you're okay.
我们想你
We miss you.
我爱你
I love you.
瞧你专注的样子
Look at you.
上帝把你带来我们身边 真是幸事啊 瑞秋
We're lucky God brought you here to us, Rachel.
你知道我不叫瑞秋
You know my name isn't Rachel.
沃特弗德太太
Mrs. Waterford.
两个月前刚见面时我就知道了
I knew when I met you two months ago.
我读过你的书
I read your book.
不论如何 我都欢迎你
And I welcomed you here anyway.
噢
Oh.
我知道人们怎么看我做的那些事
I know what people think of the things that I've done.
你如何看待你做的那些事
What do you think of the things you've done?
我想为上帝的荣耀奉献自己
I wanted to serve the glory of God.
只是这样吗
Was that all?
可惜事与愿违
Well, it didn't go as planned.
形势急转直下
It went wrong.
情况失控了
All by itself.
是我错了
I was wrong.
那就亲手修正它
So, set it right.
你知道祂在看
You know He's watching.
我希望能有更多时间帮你打理玫瑰
I wish I had more time to tend to your roses, but...
可我真的太忙了
I've just been so busy.
有大事要发生了 爸爸
Something big is about to happen, Dad.
我们将改变这个国家
We're about to change the country.
我们终于能践行上帝的圣言
We're finally living up to God's Word, and...
整个世界将成为新的伊甸园
and the whole world is going to become a new Garden of Eden.
就像你一直想要的那样
Just like you always wanted.
你还真是音信全无
You don't write. You don't call.
祈神保佑 约瑟夫
Blessed day, Joseph.
祈神保佑 赛丽娜
Blessed day, Serena.
内奥米
Naomi?
现在是劳伦斯太太了
Mrs. Lawrence.
这里不是基列国 大主教
This isn't Gilead, Commander.
您这是擅闯他人领地
You're trespassing.
我们并无恶意
We come in peace.
只需叨扰片刻
Just need a little of your time.
所以 现在有劳伦斯太太了
So... Mrs. Lawrence.
是啊 帕特南不幸离世了
Yeah, Putnam came to an unfortunate end.
我倒并不惊讶
I can't say that I'm surprised.
很惬意啊
Well, this is cute.
这里只有女人吗
It's only women?
这是一个互帮互助 侍奉上帝的社区
It's a community that supports each other and serves God.
男人总把事情弄得一团糟
Men make a mess of things.
你快无聊死了吧
You're bored outta your mind.
我希望你能来新伯利恒
I need you in New Bethlehem.
我需要赛丽娜·乔伊·沃特弗德
I need Serena Joy Waterford.
你说过像我这样的女人在基列国没有立足之地
You told me there was no place for a woman like me in Gilead.
要是你知道我错了 应该会很开心
You'll be happy to know it turns out that I was wrong.
新伯利恒不是你记忆中的基列国
New Bethlehem is not the Gilead you remember.
它更友善温和
It's kinder, gentler.
它是理想中的基列国
It's what Gilead could have been.
是在你的协助下能到达的理想乡
It's what it could become with your help.
你会成为进步的代言人
And you would be the face of progress.
改革即将展开
Reform.
我能拍摄更多宣传照了
More photo ops?
拜托 赛丽娜
Come on, Serena.
你很清楚 我知道你远不只是个花瓶
You know that I know that you're much more than a pretty face.
你不是摆设 你会拥有真正的话语权
No, you'd have real influence.
我保证你能独立自主
I promise you. Independence.
我是个带孩子的女人
As a woman with a child,
你知道我会被强制再婚
you know that I would be forced to remarry.
在新伯利恒 女人们可以独立生活
Women can live on their own in New Bethlehem.
她们能阅读 写作 经商
They can read, write, do business.
原来女人能做好多事 真是令人惊讶
Turns out it's crazy what women are capable of.
是吗
Hmm.
我不确定 我在这里能感觉到上帝
I don't know. I feel God here.
在那里就感受不到了吗
Well, can't you feel him there?
我还以为上帝无处不在 如果不在就把祂带去呗
I thought God was everywhere. If not, bring him along.
做其他人的明灯
Show other people the way.
这不就是你的理想和使命吗 赛丽娜
Isn't that your true purpose, Serena? Isn't that your calling?
眼目知道你们在哪
The Eyes know where you are.
惠勒夫妇迟早也会知道
It's only a matter of time before the Wheelers do too.
慢着
Hold on.
你昨天和前天都来过了
You were here yesterday and the day before.
我打不通 好吗 情况紧急
I couldn't get through, okay? It's an emergency.
大家都情况紧急 排队等吧
Yeah. They're all emergencies. Wait in line.
拜托了 这是最后一次 我保证
Come on. It's the last time. Promise.
快接 快接 快接
Come on, come on, come on.
马克 我是琼
Mark. It's June.
我给你打电话是因为
I'm calling 'cause...
你说
Mm-hmm.
- 你说五月天 - 是啊
- Mayday? - Yeah.
他们自愿加入了
They fucking volunteered.
他们要干什么
To do what?
我不知道 只知道卢克和莫伊拉
I don't know. And now, Luke and Moira
如今困在无人区 没人救得出来
are stuck in No Man's Land, and they can't get them out.
天呐
My God.
那你这又是干什么
Well, what are you doing?
美国大使馆的人会带我过去
The American Embassy's gonna fly me out.
- 我去帮忙救他们出来 - 你在说什么胡话
- I'm gonna help get them back. - What are you talking about?
你又不是什么间谍 又不是当兵的
You're not a spy. You're not a soldier.
呃 你可能对我干过的事儿不太了解 妈
Ah, you don't really know what I've done, Mom.
那就告诉我
Then tell me.
好 有一个大主教 他在跟美国人合作
Okay. There's a Commander, and he's working with the Americans now.
他能帮忙 但是他最近一直不接美国打给他的电话
He can help, but he has stopped responding to their calls.
然后呢
So?
我能让他开口
He'll respond to me.
他是妮可的父亲吗
Is he Nichole's father?
所以你是他的使女
So you were his Handmaid.
不 不是
No, no.
他是我当时大主教家的司机
No, he was my Commander's driver.
司机都是眼目
Drivers are Eyes.
他当时是眼目 现在是个大主教
He was an Eye, and now, he's a Commander?
好吧
Okay.
你当时的选择是迫不得已
You did what you had to do.
但这个男人 你不能信任他
But this man, you cannot trust him.
这有可能是个陷阱 就是为了抓到你和妮可
This could be a trap to get you and Nichole.
不 不可能
No, no, no.
尼克很爱妮可
Nick, He loves Nichole.
他真的 他很爱妮可的
He really... He loves Nichole.
他...不是那样的人
He's... He's not like that.
男人都一样
They're all like that.
都是禽兽
They're monsters!
不 他不是的 他是例外
No, not him. No, not him.
你在自欺欺人
You're lying to yourself!
哪怕是我亲手包扎的伤员 我都知道他们是禽兽
Even when I was patching 'em up, I knew what they were.
那我该怎么做 我应该把他们扔在那不管吗
Right, so what should I do? Should I leave them there?
让卢克和莫伊拉等着被抓 被毒打 被处决吗
Leave Luke and Moira there to get caught? Tortured? Executed?
一定有别的办法
There has to be another way.
没有别的办法了
There is no other way.
唯一的办法就是亲自上场战斗 这是你教我的
The only way is to show up and to fight, which is what you taught me!
我说的是错的
And I was wrong!
我为此失去了很多
I lost!
我放弃了那么多跟你相处的时间
I gave up so much time with you!
为此我悔不当初
And, God, do I regret it!
你能做的只有好好活下来 然后才能保护你爱的人
All you can do is survive and protect the people that you love.
我现在就是要去保护他们
That is what I am doing!
而你的这位大主教 这个尼克 他也是你要保护的爱人吗
And this Commander, this Nick, is he one of those people?
你根本...
You have...
你根本不知道我经历了什么
You have no idea what you're talking about.
你不懂 完全不懂
Not... No.
我知道我女儿睡了一个独裁上位者
I know my daughter fucked a Nazi
现在还要飞过整个国家去见他
and is running across the country to see him again.
- 你闭嘴 - 你想去是吧 可以
- Fuck you. - You want to go? Fine.
你要去就去
Go ahead.
但要把孩子留在我这
But leave that child here with me.
为什么 你也要抛弃她一次吗
Why? So you can abandon her too?
妈
Mom.
这桌饭菜看起来太美味了
Well, this just looks delicious.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
谢谢你们愿意...分享
Thank you for... for sharing.
不用谢 我的餐桌欢迎所有人
Well, all are welcomed at my table.
你想说餐前祷告词吗
Would you like to say grace?
呃 我...
Um... I'm...
我比较喜欢默默祷告
I'm more of a pray-in-silence kind of guy.
这种事情对我来说非常私密
It's deeply personal to me.
好吧
Okay.
劳伦斯太太呢
Mrs. Lawrence.
好啊
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗯...
Well...
谢谢你 主
Thank you, God.
呃
Uh...
谢谢你赐予我们这顿美餐
For this blessed meal.
谢谢你的爱
And for Your love.
还有 谢谢赐予我们这些新朋友
And... for these new friends,
在这个地方
in this place.
还有...呃...各种东西
And, uh... the things.
出自《圣经·罗马书》第8章第28节和第30节
我们知晓 为了爱神的人
And we know that all things work together for the good,
就是按祂旨意蒙召的人
for those who love God,
万事都互相效力 使他们得益处
for those who are called, according to His purpose.
所召来的人 又称他们为义
And for whom He has called, He has also justified.
所称为义的人 又使他们得荣耀
And for whom He has justified, He has also glorified,
源于《耶利米书》第29章第11节和第14节的内容
因为祂赐下盼望和未来
for He gives us hope and a future.
祂将我们从流放之地汇聚起来
He gathers us all together from the places He has banished,
必使我们从流亡中归回
and He will bring us back from exile.
- 阿门 - 阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
我想要感谢在座的每一位
I want to thank everybody here
在我和诺亚一无所有 无处可去的时候
for welcoming Noah and I...
欢迎我们来到了这里
when we had nothing and nowhere to go.
你们打开了房门和心扉接纳了我们
You opened up your homes and your hearts,
你们的好意 我永远会铭记在心
and for that, I am forever grateful.
但现在 我们该走了
But now it is time for us to leave.
主对我另有安排
God has a plan for me,
就像圣经中的以利亚 摩西 和诺亚一样
just like he did with Elijah, and Moses, and Noah.
我不能再对主的安排视而不见了
And I cannot hide from His plan anymore.
这世界正在崩塌 而我
The world is broken, and...
我受天命将它愈合
I am being called to heal it.
之前我每次打电话想找你的时候
Every time that I tried to find you,
听到的都是搪塞的说辞
I got the runaround or...
或是答录机 或者干脆没人接
some recording or no answer at all, I...
那时候我会松一口气
I felt a little relief.
因为如果没人知道你在哪 说明
Because if no one could tell me where you were, it meant...
你可能还在某个地方活着
You could still be alive somewhere.
如果真的接通 有人告诉我你已经不在了...
But if I got through, and someone said you were gone...
相信你还活着 这份信念支撑我活到今天
Holding on to the hope that you were alive kept me going.
而你才刚刚回到我身边啊
And I just got you back.
我不能再失去你了
I can't lose you again.
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean what I said.
我知道你没有抛弃我
I know you didn't abandon me.
我知道的
I know that.
我知道你必须过去
I know you need to go.
我也知道我当时不是一个很好的母亲
And I know I wasn't the mother I should have been.
但求求你 琼
But, please, June.
把她留在我这里吧
Please leave her here with me.
我保证 我会尽全力照顾好她
I promise you, I will take care of her with every fiber of my being.
我当年没能照顾好你
I wasn't there for you.
还有汉娜
Or Hannah.
这次让我照顾她吧 求你了
Let me be there for her, please.
好吧 不会很久的 知道吧
Okay. It's not for long, okay?
我会过去那边
Because I'm gonna... I'm gonna go there,
把他们救出来
and I'm gonna get them,
然后我立刻就回来 好吗
and then I'm gonna come right back. All right?
我和妮可会一直在这里等你
And Nichole and I will be right here waiting for you.
好
Okay.
妮可
Nichole.
妈妈
Mom.
她出生的时候
When she was born...
我给她起了你的名字
I named her after you.
她的名字是霍莉
Her name is Holly.
那才是她的真名
It's her real name.
妈妈要出门一段时间 好吗
Mommy's gonna have to go for a little while, okay?
但是我很快就会回来
But I'm gonna be back really soon.
我会带着爸爸 还有莫伊拉阿姨回来
And I'm gonna bring back Daddy, and Auntie Moira,
到时候我们全都和姥姥住在一起 好吗
and we're all gonna be here together with Grandma, right?
喜欢吗 你真棒
You like that? Look at that.
你想把它拿过来吗
You wanna bring this over?
这是什么
What's that?
你想把它放上去吗
Oh, you wanna put that on there?
好了
There we go.
真棒
Perfect!
欢迎来到新伯利恒
Radiohead - Burn the Witch
♪停留在黑暗中♪
Stay in the shadows
♪在绞架下雀跃♪
Cheer at the gallows
♪这是一场围捕♪
This is a roundup
♪这是一场小型恐慌发作♪
This is a low-flying panic attack
♪点一首歌来唱 歌词是♪
Sing a song on the jukebox that goes
♪烧死♪
Burn
♪那个女巫♪
The witch
♪烧死♪
Burn
♪那个女巫♪
The witch
♪我们知道♪
We know
♪你住在哪里♪
Where you live
♪木门上画了红色的叉♪
Red crosses on wooden doors
♪如果你漂浮起来 就要被烧死♪
And if you float, you burn
♪闲言碎语绕满桌♪
Loose talk around tables
♪常理逻辑抛脑后♪
Abandon all reason
♪躲开目光接触♪
Avoid all eye contact
♪不要轻举妄动♪
Do not react
♪传递消息的人也要死♪
Shoot the messengers
♪这是一场小型恐慌发作♪
This is a low-flying panic attack
♪唱首六便士之歌♪
Sing the song of sixpence that goes
♪烧死♪
Burn
♪那个女巫♪
The witch
♪烧死♪
Burn
♪那个女巫♪
The witch
♪我们知道♪
We know
♪你住在哪里♪
Where you live
♪我们知道♪
We know
♪你住在哪里♪
Where you live
嗨
Hey.
我叫琼
My name is June.
我们带他们回家
Let's bring them home.